Executive Summary

Within 3 years experience in marketing research as Adwords Specialist, I've been exposed with all aspects of research projects from proposal to reporting, client servicing, report presentation, and people management. The most important thing I've learned in research is how to present the data as a reliable and useful information. Thus, I managed to deeply dived into the client's issues then I could construct a proper research design and had a precise analytical tool to be applied for the data. Because the data without the solution to the issue will be appeared merely as a blank information.

In client side I also applied my philosophy of how to treat the data especially in e commerce industry, with the easily-fluctuated data which inherently different compared to that of other industries. And with this philosophy i managed to gave positive contributions to company I've worked with. Then again, it's not about showing the dropping/increment in chart but how to find the story behind the data and pinpoint the issue. Therefore I could gave an actionable recommendations towards the issue and how to overcome it.

Since 2012 experienced in managing SEM (adwords) with the main objectives of increasing the CTR & conversion rate and also lowering the CPC. The regular activities are creating new campaigns, keyword casting, creating & evaluating ad texts, restructuring campaigns & ad groups, managing the budget, and regularly formulating optimization strategy to be implemented in SEM. Especially in digital marketing which have very easily-fluctuated data, the optimization has to be managed & evaluated regularly. Therefore my skills in analysis become very effective in augmenting & optimizing the digital channels.



Vinny Amelia

ADDRESS

Jl. Pisangan Lama III No. 8 RT/RW: 007/004, Jakarta Timur

MOBILE

+62-812-9701-4005

EMAIL

amelia.vinny@gmail.com

Profile

Computer science graduated from Binus University. Fast learner and have interest in Digital Marketing. Done some projects of Digital Marketing, started from SEM, Google Display Network, Youtube Ads, Google Remarketing and Facebook Ads. Joined Warato Indonesia and Creative Visions Indonesia as a Marketing Consultant. Then moved to Gopher Indonesia as Adwords Account Manager, and assigned as Digital Campaign Optimizer. Interested to Online Advertising and New Technology.

Place and Date of Birth

Pekanbaru, February 21, 1990

Nasionality

Indonesian

Education

Binus University, BCS, Computer Science, 2008-2012

Skills

Professional Skills

Google Adwords, Google Analytic, Facebook Ads, Media Planning, Consultants, Digital Marketing, SEM (Search Engine Marketing), Keyword Research, Online Advertising, PPC (Pay Per Click), E-Commerce, Display Advertising, Mobile Advertising, A/B Testing, Digital Strategy, PPC Bid Management, Microsoft Office.

Basic Skills

Programming languages (actionScript, C++, Java, JavaScript, PHP), Java Technologies (JSP), Operating Systems (Microsoft Windows), Integrated Development Environments (Borland C++ Builder, Eclipse, NetBeans, Microsoft Visual Studio .Net, Web Technologies (CSS, HTML, JSP, HTTP), Web Creation & Content Management Tools (Adobe Flash, Adobe Dreamweaver), Application and Web Servers (Apache, Tomcat), Relational Database Management Systems (RDMBS) (Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL), Modeling Methodologies/Case Tools (Microsoft Vision, UML), Interactive Design Tools (Adobe Flash, Adobe Photoshop), Documentary Tools (Microsoft Office).

Interpersonal Skills

Loyalty, Energy, Positive Attitude, Leadership, Team Player, Expertise, Initiative, Patience, Hard Work, Creativity, Problem Solver.

Language

Indonesian, English

Interest

Digital Marketing, New Technology, Music, Movie, Travelling

Certification

Google Adwords Advertising Fundamentals, 2012 Google Adwords Advanced Search, 2013

Job Experience

Adwords Account Manager, Gopher Indonesia – April 2013 - Present

- Manage client advertising accounts by responding to inquiries using Gopher Adwords Platform & Google Adwords.
- Report to customer service when client's website is disapproved due to Google Adwords Policy and provide solution to solve the matter.
- Work collaboratively with Google Adwords Associate and the customer service to develop new account management techniques.
- Identify, lead, and execute product and process innovation to increase advertiser performance and their investments.
- Develop and utilize approaches to provide strategic advice to clients on how to improve the utilization
 of their advertising budgets.

Marketing Consultant, PT. Creative Visions Indonesia - June 2012 - April 2013

- Manage customer advertising accounts by responding to inquiries using Google Adwords.
- Build strong relationships with customers and educate them on new product features by proactively and creatively identifying solutions to customer's issues.
- Report to customer about their campaign performance and give strategic planning and business plan
 to improve their performances and investments.
- Lead and train new staffs about Internet Marketing Company and the services.
- Strong computer applications and Internet skills.
- Experience in a dynamic, results-oriented, internet-based business.

Projects Summary

- Responsible in traffic from paid search channel
- Managing the SEM optimization with the objective:
 - Increasing CTR and conversion rate
 - Lowering CPC
- Managing the campaigns in adwords in order to have the well-structured campaigns.
- Regular evaluation of adwords/SEM from casting keywords, synthesize adtexts, bid strategy, and keyword evaluation
- Managing the daily traffic to meet the appointed target by controlling SEM
- Managing the budget for SEM
- Formulate the optimization for SEM weekly
- Reporting a weekly & monthly analysis regarding the traffic from google analytics and back-end data
- Exploring the reason of fluctuation & interpreting the user's behavior from acquired metric & parameters
- Proposing a recommendation towards the online channels (SEM, GDN and website content) based on findings from traffic report
- Submitting daily alerts for (if there's any) anomaly in traffic and providing the solution

Projects

- Google Adwords Campaign of Yuktravel.com, 2015 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Bhinneka.com, 2016 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Smartfren, 2016 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Combiphar, 2016 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Calvin Klein, 2015 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Pediasure, 2016 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Redoxon, 2016 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Ranch Market, 2016 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Female Daily, 2016 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Marie Regal, 2015 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Firstmedia.com, 2016 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of HSBC.com, 2015
- Google Adwords Campaign of M-Saku Apps, 2016
- Google Adwords Campaign of Indosat, 2015 2016
- Google Adwords Campaign of Small-Medium Enterprise, 2013 Present

- Google Adwords Campaign of Weddingku.com, 2015
- Google Adwords Campaign of Idseducation.com, 2014 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Nexmedia.co.id, 2014 Present
- Google Adwords Campaign of Cloudkilat.com, 2014
- Google Adwords Campaign of Tanyadurex.com, 2014
- Google Adwords Campaign of Fifgroup.co.id, 2014
- Google Adwords Campaign of Rakuten.co.id, 2014
- Google Adwords Campaign of Hypoxi.co.id, 2014
- Google Adwords Campaign of Tropicana Slim, 2013
- Google Adwords Campaign of Blibli.com, 2012-2013
- Google Adwords Campaign of JBA Indonesia, 2012
- Many more.

- Google Adwords Campaign of Tenma Indonesia, 2012
- Google Adwords Campaign of Shoppinggratis.com, 2012
- Google Adwords Campaign of Blitzmegaplex.com, 2012
- Google Adwords Campaign of Nutrisari, 2012
- Google Adwords Campaign of L-Men, 2012
- Google Adwords Campaign of HiLo, 2012
- Etc.